♪
[RIGHT]
On the day of the equinox,
a twin boy and girl
will be born,
dividing the sunrise,
destined to command the daemons.
[LEFT] So is said
in that eastern village.
And these twins will
not only sunder night and day,
-but the whole world.
-[infants crying]
[RIGHT] Some 400 years ago,
a great war tore
the nation in twain,
with those who wield daemons
pulling the strings.
The people of Higashi tried
to keep the twins
inside their village,
hoping to make use
of their powers.
Their parents realized
the children were in danger
as things stood,
so they made plans
to flee the village.
But try though as they might,
they only managed
to escape with Asa.
The twins have powers
that are their right to claim.
Break and Seal.
One, the ability
to forcibly unravel all things.
That is the power of Break.
[LEFT] The other, the ability
to forcibly close all things.
That is Seal.
[ASA] If I had any choice,
I wouldn't be a twin fated
to fulfill some prophecy.
But now, I can choose.
And I'll get my own hands dirty.
[RIGHT] After she gained
the power of Break,
Asa attacked the village
to take back her brother.
Get away from her!
[LEFT] Amidst the chaos,
we were awoken
from our 400-year slumber.
[RIGHT] And luckily,
our new boss
is the hands-off type.
[DERA] Yuru...
these are your daemons.
[RIGHT] Asa is being sheltered
by a group known
as the Kagemoris.
[LEFT] A subsect of Higashi,
who split over irreconcilable
differences.
[RIGHT] Yuru was offered
a place with their clan,
but chose to search
for his parents
without their help.
[YURU] I'm not gonna live
my life on the run!
And I have got
no reason to hide!
I don't care if you're from
Higashi or the Kagemoris.
I'm not afraid.
If you want my head,
come and get it!
[LEFT] And by appearances,
even their own clan
isn't a monolith.
[ASA] The truth is...
I died once.
[GONZO] Humanity is better off
without Break or Seal.
They are too great a threat.
And since we share their blood,
it's our responsibility
to make sure
they're taken care of.
The village that produces
Break and Seal
should be allowed to live on.
We mustn't reject
their very existence.
[RIGHT]
And it seems other forces
are throwing themselves
into the fray.
We must tread carefully.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[MAN] Yes, sir.
I followed him partway up.
Only as far as you said.
Yes, by my estimation
the "shaman"
should be inside by now.
[SHINGO] Good. Well done.
I just needed to know
when he arrived in the village.
Wait there for further orders.
Hey, Ivan...
-You're up.
-[Ivan exhales]
[IVAN] Aye-aye, sir.
Time to get to it, Shokyo.
[SHOKYO] Excuse me?
You mean, "Please aid me,
Master Shokyo!"
Come on, tell me who's
the master of who again here?
[SHOKYO] Silence, monkey!
I'll fillet you like a fish!
[IVAN] Daikyo, talk some sense
into your other half.
[DAIKYO] Mm...
[IVAN] Look at me
when I talk to you.
You two sure like
acting high and mighty
for a couple of daemons
who aren't even able to move
without a master.
[SHOKYO] The insolence!
Your simian brain
could do nothing
if it weren't for our help!
Who do you think's putting food
on your table?
That's me, you lazybones.
I thought you were sharp.
-[SHOKYO] Screw you, baboon!
-[SHINGO] Shut up!
Get a move on!
I'm not payin' you a fortune
so you can talk my ear off!
[IVAN] Yeah, yeah.
In we go.
This shouldn't take me
terribly long.
Man, that's creepy.
[birds chirping]
[KEN] Hmm. So, does this look
any better?
-A ton!
-[HANA] What's up?
Are you making weapons again?
[YURU] Uh, yeah.
[DERA] All right!
Then I'd better give you
something to do.
What's this metal board?
[DERA] The old tube.
It's square.
[beeps]
And looking at the south end...
[Yuru exclaims]
-[RIGHT] Whoa!
-[LEFT] Mm.
-...nothing but scattered...
-[Yuru exclaims]
Some are concerned we may see
a water shortage
in the western part
of the country.
Next, we have
the national forecast.
In Okinawa,
we expect to see
clear blue skies...
Oh, yeah. I can't visit
the place my mother's from.
...make sure
you pack some shorts...
What about you?
You mean me?
The place you said
you two were from.
Ethio... something?
[chuckles] You mean Ethiopia.
It's in Africa.
[RIGHT] Mm?
[YURU] Don't you wanna go
visit sometimes?
Eh...
it's pretty ridiculously
far away.
I could, though.
And I shouldn't take that
for granted, now should I?
There's no way I could go back
to Higashi Village now.
It's not safe.
[birds chirping]
[bird screeching]
[YURU] But I left so much
behind back there.
I wish I could see it again.
[Yama yelps]
[YAMA] No! What's going on here?
Hey, shaman.
[Yama yelps]
You wait right there.
Be back in a jiff.
[SHOKYO] Oi, monkey.
I can sense them.
There are daemons in the keep.
All the way up there, huh?
There's a saying about fools
and something
liking high places.
[SHOKYO] It's fools and monkeys.
[IVAN] It's fools
and smoke, you fool.
[SHOKYO]
You dare call me a fool, fool?
[exhales]
♪
[breathes uneasily]
[man laughs]
That's pretty rough, buddy.
Yeah, you're tellin' me.
[BOTH] Hm?
-[MAN 1] You know that guy?
-[MAN 2] Nope.
What's your name?
-How'd you get in here?
-[clanging]
-[MAN 2] Hey...
-[both grunt]
No daemons.
[man whimpers]
[screams]
How annoying.
[slashing]
[man grunting]
-[slashing]
-[man groans]
[thuds]
Not him either.
[men yelling]
-[IVAN] Nope. Nada.
-[men grunting]
[IVAN] Bzz... None of them.
Not even one.
[sword slashing]
[Ivan gasps]
[grunting]
That was quite a greeting.
[all gasp]
Who are you?
Are you with those raiders
from the last time?
We have people watching
every possible entrance.
How'd you get inside?
And without even
breaking the barrier!
[men grunting]
[Yamaha gasps]
Look at you.
I heard about some daemon
they had bound in a cage.
-You look like Asa.
-[grunts]
You let me cut straight
through those guys,
but came to save the old lady?
[Yamaha grunts]
I suppose that means
she's your master.
[Ivan gasps]
Didn't miss a beat attacking me!
You realize
I've got your master?
If she's a daemon,
her other half must be nearby.
But where? Stay on guard!
[SHOKYO] Uh? Look down, monkey!
[Ivan grunts]
[gasps]
[Asa (fake) sighs]
Why you gotta do me like that,
Shokyo? Good grief.
[SHOKYO] What?
You're saying that one leg
was worth more than your life?
You should be kneeling
on your hands and knees
thanking your savior!
And how do you expect me
to kneel on this leg? Hm?
So you're the fake Asa?
But you're made
to look a lot more childlike
than the real deal.
You throw this cute
and defenseless little burden
at that big brother,
and there's no chance
he'd ever wanna run away.
Messed up, if you ask me.
And not one of these villagers
could see daemons.
Did she keep it like that
on purpose?
Hoard all the power,
so these poor chumps
have no choice
but to worship her?
Your master's
not just messed up.
She's downright repulsive.
Anyway, guess
I can't kill your master,
'cause then you'd become
a stray.
It's that face I want,
so I won't have you going back
to your original form.
I could contract you myself.
But my pair, Magatsuhi,
just wouldn't like that.
More specifically, Shokyo here's
incompatible with everyone.
Worst case,
short stuff might straight up
kill you just for fun.
[SHOKYO] Oh, I'd kill her.
Well, you heard the sword.
Now if you come quietly
without complaining,
I'll do you a solid
and spare your master's life.
So hop to it, you phony.
Down there?
Off the mountain.
It'll be fun.
Uh?
♪
[sighs]
[Asa (fake) grunts]
[ASA (FAKE)] You win.
-I'll go.
-[Yamaha gasps]
[sighs]
[footsteps]
[IVAN] The other half
of this pair never wound up
making their grand entrance.
I wonder why.
Are they up to something?
I'd like a human hostage
for insurance, too.
[all crying]
[screaming]
[Azami whimpers]
Now there's a child
who won't struggle!
[boy crying]
[boy crying] Mommy!
Please, get up!
-Not again.
-Awful.
Our little village might not
bounce back from this attack.
[grunts] We need
to get away now!
The monster's still here!
Danji, remember
you used to tell me
you'd like to see
the world outside with Yuru?
[gasps] Yeah?
It's time now.
You're going down there.
By yourself.
Wait, you don't mean...
You can't, Ma! What about you?
I am staying in the village.
You boys might come home
one day.
You'll need someone to welcome
you back with open arms,
and that's me.
But Mama...
Here, I wrote you directions
to help get down the mountain.
Follow each one to a tee.
[Danji breathes shakily]
I'm going to be fine.
Yuru needs you,
so get outta here.
And if you do see
Mine and Nagisa,
give them my regards.
[Yama grunting]
Who was that?
What's he after?
I want no part
of whatever's happening here!
[both chirping]
[Yama grunts]
[Tsugais shrieking]
[Yama gasps]
I believe I said you were
to wait right where I left you.
[Yama whimpers]
[Yama grunts]
[Azami whimpers]
You two go ahead without me.
[both whimpering]
[Asa (Fake) gasps]
Welcome to the outside world.
[Azami whimpers]
[Tsugais growl]
[Yama whimpers]
Well, I didn't have
another exit route planned out.
-[Yama gasps]
-[both shriek]
Too bad. Looks like
I need myself a guide.
Maybe a kind shaman
could help me.
What do you say?
[Danji panting, grunting]
[Danji grunts]
[wings fluttering]
[Danji groans]
[DANJI] Am I outside?
Yuru!
Where's Yuru?
He needs me!
[gasps]
[horse neighs]
Hello! Want a lift?
[DANJI] Wait.
You know the Divine Guardians?
[OSHIRASAMA] That's right.
We have been friends
a long time.
In fact, I came across them
fleeing the village
with the boy twin
just the other day!
Boy twin? That's Yuru!
They said they would hide
inside a busy human town.
They were riding in a car.
A what now?
[Danji gasps] Huh?
[OSHIRASAMA] Yes! One of those!
[DANJI] Good.
Yuru made it
down the mountain safely.
Thank all the gods.
But I still don't know
where I can find him.
Hmm, let me see.
The license plate on their car
was registered to the capital.
It may be best to search there!
-Shall we?
-Uh, what?
How exciting!
I've never been to the capital!
Oh, first things first!
I had best tell my master
before we go!
May we stop by my home first?
[DANJI] Uh, yeah, sure.
[horse neighs]
[OSHIRASAMA'S MASTER]
How nice!
You're taking a trip to see
some friends who live far away?
And I have company!
My friend's master's friend
is here, too!
[DANJI] Hello, ma'am! Uh?
[chuckles]
My, oh, my...
What a charming young man
you've found.
Please do take care now.
[horse neighs]
[OSHIRASAMA'S MASTER]
Watch out for cars on the road.
Be careful not to scare
ordinary folks!
Right. I'll see you later.
And remember to actually enjoy
your time in the city!
[OSHIRASAMA] May I really?
-Ooh! Yippee!
-[horse neighs]
Okay! Let's get
the highway experience!
What?
The highway?
[OSHIRASAMA] Mm-hmm.
[Danji screaming]
[OSHIRASAMA] Yay!
-[Oshirasama laughing]
-[Danji screaming]
Shall we stop by the rest area?
[Danji continues screaming]
[mobile phone chirps]
All right. What have we here?
[grunts]
Dera, heads up.
I've got some
extra work tonight.
Sure. Take it easy out there.
And you should know,
the shaman was killed.
[DERA] Hmm.
[BANDIT] By the time
we got to his shop,
it was already too late.
The shaman was long dead.
Ooh, boy, what a casket.
Something this size
won't be easy to bury.
I hope you know I'm gonna have
to charge you extra for this.
Oh, yeah.
Didn't the shaman have
a couple of daemons of his own?
Are they stuck somewhere
as strays?
[BANDIT] Oh, you mean
Lady and Gentleman.
[birds chirping]
[BANDIT] We found them chopped
in half right beside him.
[HANA] That's terrible.
Poor little guys
weren't even fighters.
Do you happen
to have their relics?
I'll bury them with him.
Will it cost us extra?
Nah, this one's on the house.
Anyway, one thing
before you bury him...
[Hana grunts]
[HANA] "Dear Yuru, I have your
fake sister and a village child.
On the next full moon
at the hour of the Boar,
come to
Fujimurayama warehouse one."
Did the Kagemoris do this?
No clue.
We heard from him.
Got a couple of texts
just before he made
his trip to Higashi.
He said that Tadera
was keeping Yuru down here
after they ran away
from the village.
We had also heard the Kagemoris
made contact with him.
I don't suppose you know
where this secret hideaway is?
Who, me? Just what do you think?
Dera called me
as his getaway driver,
and after I picked up those two,
I dropped 'em off
at the usual safehouse.
Didn't tell me jack about
where he was going after that.
You know how he likes
to keep to himself.
Hmm, checks out.
Oh, well. There's nothing else
you can do.
That said,
if you see Dera or Yuru,
don't give them this message.
Us "bandits" are gonna scope
the place out.
Whoever did this
can't find Yuru.
No matter what.
[HANA] That's just my luck.
This job keeps bein'
a pain in my ass.
[DANJI] Oshirasama!
I'm begging you!
Please, please, please!
Please, let me down!
Let me down! [cries]
Don't tell me you're scared
of heights, Danji!
This is too much!
The capital is too much! [cries]
Hang on a little longer!
I'm trying to find
Left and Right for you.
Their presence is so much
more powerful than most.
They should be quite easy
to track from way up here.
Oh, wow!
I know we have
plenty back home.
[Danji gasps]
[OSHIRASAMA] But the capital
is just swarming with daemons,
isn't it?
[bird screeching]
♪
[Hana sighs]
[BANDIT] That said,
if you see Dera or Yuru,
don't give them this message.
Yeah, yeah. Don't gotta tell me.
I'd like a peaceful life,
thank you very much.
[sighs]
Fools and smoke rise
to high places, as they say.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[DERA] So, who do you think
killed him?
[RIGHT] There be daemons nearby.
[YURU] We'll take care
of this here.
[HANA] There were some words
carved into the shaman's body.